No.
不
It can't be.
不可能
It isn't true.
这不是真的
Um, Twilight?
呃, 暮光?
Twilight!
暮光!
The bus for Camp Everfree leaves in ten minutes!
去森灵营地的校车还有十分钟就要走了!
Oh no no no no no!
哦, 不不不不!
I can't believe I overslept!
真不敢相信我睡过头了!
Me neither. That's not like you.
我也不信 这可不像你的作风
I know!
我知道!
Don't you have a super-annoying alarm clock that goes omm-omm-omm-omm?
你不是有一个超级烦人的闹钟吗, 就像嗯——嗯——嗯的叫
It's gonna be fine.
没事的
We'll help you pack.
我们来帮你打包
Eh.
唉
We're gonna be out in the woods.
我们可是要待在森林里
When's she gonna need that?
她怎么会需要这个?
If we were going to the moon, I'd insist she'd pack an evening gown.
如果我们想玩得尽兴的话, 我就必须要坚持她带一套晚礼服
One never knows, darling.
指不定就用上了呢, 亲爱的
Lemme just get changed.
让我先换件衣服
Midnight Sparkle?!
午夜闪闪?!
How is this possible?
这怎么可能?
Sunset Shimmer helped me defeat you at the Friendship Games!
余晖烁烁帮助我在友谊大赛中战胜了你!
You and your friends can never truly defeat me!
你和你的朋友们永远都不可能真正地战胜我!
Midnight Sparkle's a part of you!
午夜闪闪是你的一部分!
I'll always be there,
我会一直存在的
waiting in the darkest shadows of your mind!
在你心底的最阴暗之处潜伏着的!
I'll be back, Twilight!
我会回来的, 暮光!
And this time, I won't stop until I have all the magic!
这次, 不得到所有的魔力我誓不罢休!
No!
不!
STOP!
停下!
Twilight, wake up!
暮光, 醒醒!
We can't stop, silly!
我们不能停, 小傻瓜!
We're not there yet!
我们还没到站呢!
Hey, are you okay?
嘿, 你没事吧?
Heh. I'm fine.
恩, 没事
We are gonna have so much fun!
我们会玩得很高兴的!
We're gonna roast marshmallows and eat marshmallows and sleep on marshmallow pillows!
我们要烤棉花糖然后吃棉花糖然后枕着棉花糖睡觉!
Yeah, probably not gonna do that.
哈, 八成不会这么做
Maybe you're not.
也许你不会
Attention, students,
注意, 同学们
we're almost there.
我们马上就要到目的地了
But before we arrive,
不过在此之前
we just wanted to say how proud we are of you for raising enough money to go on this class field trip.
我们只想说我们很骄傲能看到你们筹足资金来举行这次班级野外旅游
When we were your age, we made some of our favorite memories in these woods,
当我们还是你们这个年纪时曾经在这片森林里留下了不少美好的回忆
and we're sure you will, too.
相信你们也会的
Now who's excited for Camp Everfree!
现在告诉我谁对这次露营激动万分!
习成 PBU 工作组
制作
Fedex
Loadhe & BronyDee
监制
Will you be lost by time or be part of history?
你想随时光流逝还是驻于历史?
Pinkiesparkle & Fedex
爱飞的 502
合作翻译
Will your story be told or remain a mystery?
你想流芳一世或是隐于神秘里?
奈吉尔 & 狼王.shadow
ruzx007878
合作翻译
Will they sing your song, telling all that you have done?
他们会不会传唱你走过的路?
HF & 彳亍游龙
合作翻译
Time to make your choice, only you can be the one
选择正当时  只有你能成为你
Pinkiesparkle
LeafyBat
润色
Oh-oh-oh-oh-whoa
LeoDango
润色
As you join in the Legend of Everfree (Hey)
当你进入这森灵的传说里 (嘿)
JohnTen
质量管理
Oh-oh-oh-oh-whoa
As you join in the Legend of Everfree
当你加入这森灵的传说里
Hey Hey Hey
Will you do something great with the time that you have here?
时间如流水清风  你怎么展飞如鹏?
BronyDee & Fedex
TlanDro
时间轴
Will you make your mark, will you conquer what you fear?
恐慌于心底盘踞  你怎么一鸣而起?
And when you go back home, everybody there will see
当你归来时  所有人都会看见
You were part of the Legend of Everfree
你活跃在那森灵的传说里
爱飞的 502
狼王.shadow
时间轴
Oh-oh-oh-oh-whoa
As you join in the Legend of Everfree (Hey)
当你进入这森灵的传说里 (嘿)
BronyDee
压制
Oh-oh-oh-oh-whoa
As you join in the Legend of Everfree (Hey)
当你加入这森灵的传说里 (嘿)
Will you find your greatest glory?
你能否赢得殊荣华丽?
饰 暮光闪闪
饰 余晖烁烁
Will you be a falling star?
你能否闪耀飞落天际?
饰 云宝黛西 & 苹果杰克
Here to learn what nature teaches
在这里学习自然智慧
饰 萍琪派 & 小蝶
Here to learn more who you are
在这里追寻你的足迹
Will you be lost by time or be part of history?
你想随时光逝去还是驻于历史?
饰 瑞瑞
Will your story be told or remain a mystery?
你想流芳一世或是隐于神秘里?
饰 斯派克
And when you go back home, everybody there will see
当你归来时  所有人都会看见
饰 嘉兰金菊
You were part of the Legend of Everfree
你活跃在那森灵的传说里
饰 云杉棕木
Oh-oh-oh-oh-whoa
As you join in the Legend of Everfree (Hey)
当你进入到森灵的传说里 (嘿)
Oh-oh-oh-oh-whoa
As you join in the Legend of Everfree
当你加入这森灵的传说里
Hey
Isn't Camp Everfree just beautiful?
森灵营地可真漂亮啊
I can't wait until we have our first nature walk.
噢, 我都等不及进行我们的第一次野外徒步了
I definitely wanna go on one of those.
我也一直想来一次野外徒步
You wanna see all the adorable woodland creatures, too?
你也想见见那些可爱的森林动物们吗?
Yeah! Specifically squirrels!
是啊! 尤其是松鼠!
More specifically, so I can chase 'em!
不过我其实更想追追它们呢!
I'm just lookin' forward to roughin' it.
我只是想来体验野外生活
I'm gonna make my own shelter, forage for food...
我要搭建我自己的庇护所、搜寻食物……
Uh, you know they provide us with food and tents, right?
呃, 你知道他们会向我们提供帐篷和食物的, 对吧?
Yup!
没错!
Still gonna forage though.
但我还是会去搜寻
I'm just after some R & R.
我就想放松放松
The past year has all been a bit too much for my taste.
这过去一年里出的事都快把我压垮了
I'll say!
可不是嘛!
We fought three evil sirens who tried to hypnotize everybody with their singing,
我们打败了三只企图用歌声催眠大家的海妖
one ridiculously competitive rival school,
一所想赢想疯了的学校
and two demon friends!
还交了两个恶魔朋友!
Uh, heh heh,
啊, 哈哈
no offense.
无意冒犯
None taken.
没关系
You'll get used to it.
你会习惯的
Yep.
对
Canterlot High has become a regular magic magnet.
坎高这地方变得越来越招惹魔法了
Gonna be nice gettin' away to a place where we don't have to worry about that kinda stuff.
能到一个不用担心这种事的地方真是太好了
Here you go, Twilight.
这个给你, 暮光
Thanks.
谢了
It's Flash, right?
你是阿绅, 对吧?
Yup, that's me!
对, 是我!
And you're you.
而且你是你
And we don't know each other very well.
而且我们不太了解对方
Cool story, bro.
不错的故事, 兄弟
Right.
恩
I guess I'll... see you around.
那么我先……回头见了
You know how there's that girl who looks just like you
你还记得有个和你长得一模一样
and she's here but lives in another dimension and she's a pony princess?
住在另一个世界并且是个小马公主的女生吗
Uh-huh.
嗯哈
Flash kinda had a... thing for her.
阿绅对她……有点意思
Oh.
噢
Hey, everyone!
嗨, 大家!
If you could start heading to the courtyard, that would be rad!
如果你们能朝院子这边走过来, 可就再好不过了!
It's time to start the best week of camp ever!
是时候开始史上最棒露营周了!
Hi, everyone! Welcome to Camp Everfree!
大家好! 欢迎来到森灵营地!
I'm Gloriosa Daisy, your camp director!
我是嘉兰金菊, 你们的营长!
Think of me as your friendly camp and nature guide.
把我当做你们亲切和蔼的营地与大自然向导就好
And this is my brother, Timber Spruce!
这是我弟弟, 云杉棕木!
Think of me as that awesome guy...
把我当成那种酷酷的
who should always be invited to fun things.
总是喜欢好玩的事情的那种人
We aim to please, so before we hand out our tent assignments,
为了你们能玩得舒心, 在我们为你们分配帐篷之前
we'd like to hear from all of you.
我们想先听听你们的想法
You're free to do whatever you like here!
在这里, 你们想干什么都可以!
Uh, except hike near the rock quarry.
啊, 但是不能跑到采石场那边去
That's off-limits.
那里是禁区
Yes, but otherwise, your options are wide open.
对, 不过除此之外, 你们可以随便提建议
So what activities will make this the very best week of your lives ever?
那么你们说什么样的活动才是最棒露营周所应该拥有的?
Ooh! Rock climbing!
噢! 攀岩!
Done!
好!
Archery!
射箭!
Of course!
肯定的!
Tetherball!
绳球!
Naturally!
当然会有!
Rainbow, I know you're excited,
云宝, 我知道你很兴奋
but maybe give somebody else a chance to make a suggestion.
但还是给别人一个说话的机会吧
Arts and crafts!
手工艺!
My mom... needs new pot holders.
我妈妈……需要新的锅垫
I'll supply the looms!
我会提供织布机!
Cookie decorating!
装饰饼干!
Why I do make a mean sugar cookie.
我能做出不错的糖屑曲奇
Early morning nature walks?
清晨散步?
With walking sticks for everyone!
已经为大家准备好了手杖!
Ooh! Me! Oh, uh...
我! 哦, 呃
a fashion show!
时装秀
Where I design the most fabulous camp looks
我要根据当今最新的时尚潮流
inspired by today's hottest trends
设计出最漂亮的营地风格时装
and have them modeled by my classmates in a gorgeous outdoor setting!
让同学们作为模特来一场精彩的室外走秀！
A camp tradition!
露营传统!
We have literally never done that.
我们可真没搞过这种活动
I'll be taking requests the rest of the time you're here,
你们在这里如果有什么需求的话随时都可以告诉我
so if there's anything you'd like to do,
所以如果你们还想做什么别的活动
anything you need,
或者有什么需要
just ask.
尽管找我吧
What about the camp gift?
营地礼物呢?
That was my favorite Camp Everfree tradition.
那是我最喜欢的森灵营地传统
The camp gift! Of course!
营地礼物! 当然了!
Really?
真的?
Yes, really.
对, 真的
Well, I just thought-
啊, 我只是想……
Then you thought wrong!
那你想错了!
Anyone else picking up on a little tension between Gloriosa and her brother?
有人注意到嘉兰和她弟弟之间有点不对劲吗?
Ehhh...
呃……
A little.
有点
Every year, campers work together to create something useful.
每一年, 营员们都会一起制作一些有用的东西
A gift for future campers.
作为给未来营员的礼物
Working toward this common goal is key to forming the strong bonds
为这个共同目标而努力
that will last well beyond your time here at camp!
是你们之间形成牢固友谊的关键
Which is why it's so important.
所以这件事很重要
This gazebo was a gift from last year's group.
这个露台是去年队伍的礼物
Oh, oh, oh, and the totem pole
噢, 噢, 噢, 还有图腾柱
and the sundial were also made by campers!
和日晷也是由营员们制造的
The sundial was our year's gift!
那日晷是我们那年的礼物!
Even though "some people" thought it was a little impractical,
虽然某些人觉得这有点不太实用
since the sundial can't be used at night.
毕竟日冕晚上不能用
Oh, you all seem like a-a really amazing group.
你们看上去是一支非常棒的团队
So I'm certain you'll come up with something inspiring to leave behind.
所以我相信你们肯定能留下些精彩的东西
Speaking of leaving things behind,
说到留下东西
now's the time when we give out tent assignments
现在我们应该给出帐篷的分配了
so you can leave your heavy bags behind.
这样你们好把行李都放好
Uh, girls will be getting their assignments from Timber.
恩, 女生们到云杉棕木那里去领取分配
Guys, you're with me.
小伙子们跟我来
Oh, boy!
哦, 天啊! 嗯……
Yay! I'm in the Emerald Tent!
耶! 我在绿宝石帐篷!
Ooh, me, too!
噢, 我也是!
Aquamarine.
海蓝宝石
Me, too!
我也是!
Yee-hoo!
耶哈!
I got Amethyst.
我是紫水晶
Sapphire.
蓝宝石
Me, too!
我也是!
I mean, I'm assuming I am.
我是说, 我认为我是
Technically, sapphires aren't just blue.
理论上来说, 蓝宝石可不只有蓝色的
They can be pink,
它们也可以是粉色的
purple,
紫色的
yellow...
黄色的
Yeah, but they're mostly blue.
对, 但是它们大多是蓝色
That's why they're named after the Latin word sapphirus.
这就是为什么人们用拉丁文 sapphirus 来命名蓝宝石
That means "blue".
意思是, 蓝色
I know.
我知道
But did you know that sapphires are just rubies without chromium?
不过你知不知道蓝宝石就是不含铬的红宝石?
No.
不知道
But did you know that Sapphire Tent is the best one?
不过你知不知道蓝宝石帐篷是最好的?
No.
不知道
Why's that?
为什么?
Because you're in it.
因为有你在
Oh, I bet you say that to all the campers.
噢, 我打赌你对所有营员都这么说
Not true.
那可不是
You're in the Ruby Tent?
你在红宝石帐篷吗?
Ha! That's the worst one!
哈! 那是最差的!
Aw, man!
真倒霉!
I'm just jokin', buddy.
只是开个玩笑, 伙计
Ruby Tent is great.
红宝石帐篷很棒
It's like a sapphire, but with chromium.
它就像蓝宝石, 但是含有铬
But the Ruby and Coral Tents do look an awful lot alike to the undiscerning eye.
但红宝石帐篷和珊瑚帐篷对于不熟悉的人来说太像了
I better show you where it is.
我还是带你过去比较好
See ya around.
回见
What?
怎么?
Heh.
哈
Nothin'.
没事
That was adorable!
噢! 真可爱!
Okay, everyone, go get settled in.
好了各位, 安顿下来吧
We'll be meeting at the docks in fifteen minutes
十五分钟后我们在码头集合
to go over some camp safety rules.
学习露营安全守则
Let me know if you need anything!
有什么需要的话就叫我吧!
I need somethin'.
我需要点东西
Filthy Rich!
臭钱!
So nice to see you.
很高兴见到你
What are you doing here?!
你来这里干什么?
Camp is just getting started!
露营刚刚开始呢!
Just takin' in the scenery, Gloriosa Daisy.
只是四处看看风景, 嘉兰金菊
It's so...
这很...
hmm...
嗯...
relaxin'.
让人放松
Well, you can look around when camp is over!
很好, 你可以在露营结束后再继续看风景!
Now, if you don't mind...
如果现在你不介意的话……
Fine.
好吧
Filthy Rich is, uh, an alumni of the camp.
臭钱他, 呃, 当年也是营员
He likes to check on his old stomping grounds every now and again.
他喜欢时不时地来他以前驻扎的地方转转
But enough about him.
不过不说他了
Find your tents and put away your things.
找到你们的帐篷, 放好东西
We've got the best week of camp ever to begin!
最棒露营周还在等着我们呢!
I'm all for learning safety rules,
我完全赞同学习安全规则
but I do hope I can get started on my designs for the camp fashion show sooner rather than later.
但我真希望我能尽早开始为露营时装秀准备设计
Huh. I still can't believe you talked Gloriosa into havin' a fashion show.
我还是不敢相信你竟然真的说服嘉兰举办时装秀了
We're in the middle of the woods, for cryin' out loud!
我们这可是在丛林腹地啊!
We're s'posed to be roughin' it!
我们应该粗野一点才对啊!
It's clear from Gloriosa's own wardrobe
从嘉兰的着装上来看
that she appreciates a well put together look.
她显然也是喜欢漂亮衣服的那类人
Even if we are in the "middle of the woods".
哪怕是我们在这“丛林腹地”里
Fair enough.
算你有理
Just as long as you don't put me in one of your fancy pants outfits.
只要你别给我穿你那些稀奇古怪的东西就行
You're gonna, aren't ya?
你打算这么做, 是吧?
No.
不会
Yes! Don't worry, darling.
才怪! 别担心, 亲爱的
It'll absolutely speak to your personal sense of style...
我给你的衣服绝对符合你的审美观……
That was weird back there, right?
刚刚那会儿很奇怪对吧?
With that guy, Filthy Rich?
就那家伙, 臭钱?
Huh?
哈?
Oh. Uh, I guess so.
噢, 呃, 我猜是吧
I just have this feeling that Gloriosa's hiding something.
我只是感觉嘉兰在隐瞒什么
Her brother is pretty cute, though, huh?
不过她弟人不错啊, 对吧
He's okay.
他还行吧
Ooooh,
喔——
now look who's trying to hide something!
有人想要隐瞒些什么哦!
No, I'm not!
不, 我才没有!
Hey, you okay?
喂 你还好吗?
You seemed a little freaked out on the bus earlier.
之前你在巴士上看起来吓坏了
Probably had another one of her nightmares.
她大概又做了个噩梦吧
I'm fine.
我没事
I mean, what do I have to complain about?
毕竟 我有什么好烦心的呢?
Ever since I transferred here, everyone from CHS has been really nice and accepting,
自从我转到坎高这边, 学校里的各位都接纳了我
especially considering what happened at the Friendship Games.
即便我在友谊大赛上做了那些事情
That wasn't your fault.
那不是你的错
Principal Cinch is the one who encouraged you to try and use all that magic to win the Games for Crystal Prep.
是严校长促使你尝试那些魔法来帮助水晶预科获取大赛胜利
You weren't ready to have that kind of power.
你还没准备好去承受那种魔力
But it's over now.
但那都已经过去了
And if there's any group that's gonna forgive you for something that happened in the past,
如果非要问会有什么人能原谅你的过错的话
trust me, it's this one.
相信我, 那就是大家
You guys comin' or what?
你们磨蹭什么呢?
Be right there!
马上来!
I just wanna put on some sunscreen.
我想擦点防晒霜
Huh. I Coulda sworn I packed it.
哈, 我明明记得带了来着
Found it!
找到啦!
Did you?
你干的?
How is this possible?
怎么做到的?
I can't believe this.
难以置信
It's...
这真是...
- Amazing!  - Terrible!
- 妙极了!   - 太糟了!
Are you kidding?
你在开玩笑吧?
This is great!
这很棒啊!
I mean, we've all ponied up before,
我是说, 我们都曾经小马化过
gotten the whole ears and wings and tail thing,
长出耳朵、翅膀和尾巴
shot magical rainbow lasers,
发射彩虹魔法激光什么的
but nothing like this has ever happened!
但这样的事情从未发生过!
How did you do it?
你怎么做到的?
I don't know!
我也不知道!
Maybe I didn't.
或许不是我
Maybe it's her!
或许是她!
Her who?
哪个她?
Nothing.
没啥
Nevermind.
算了
Can we just not talk about it?
我们能不谈论这个吗?
And could you please not bring this whole levitating thing up to the others?
以及能拜托你别把这飘浮魔法的事跟别人说吗？
Why not?
为什么啊?
You heard Applejack.
你听到苹果杰克说的话了
This is supposed to be the place where everyone can get away from magic.
这里应当是一处能让大家远离魔法的地方
I don't want them to know I brought some crazy new kind with me.
我不想让他们知道我又带来什么鬼东西了
If you really don't want me to, I won't say anything.
如果你真的不希望我告诉别人的话, 我不会说的
I really don't.
我真的不希望
Okay, but this isn't necessarily a bad thing!
行, 但这不应该算是件坏事
Omm... Omm...
I think you just gotta have to pick it up.
我想你还是捡起来吧
...show up like that!
——那样冒出来!
What did you say?
你刚刚说什么?
I... didn't say anything.
我……什么都没说啊
Just here to make sure everyone was headed over to the docks!
只是来确保每个人前往码头
Did you need something?
需要帮助么?
Nope.
不了
Because if there is anything I can do
如果有什么我能帮上忙的
to make this week the best week ever,
能让这一周成为最棒露营周的事
you just let me know.
跟我说就行
I've got this!
我会搞定的
Thanks, I'm good.
谢谢了, 我没事
People that chipper make me nervous.
那么爽朗的人让我感到紧张
This is gonna be so much fun!
这一定会很有趣的!
I guess not all people.
我猜也不是所有人都会这样
Oh, it's beautiful, isn't it?
哦 很漂亮对吧?
It looks like a diamond shining in the sun!
就像一块在阳光下闪闪发光的宝石!
It is lovely out here.
多么美丽的地方
The fresh air, the cool breeze,
新鲜的空气, 微凉的山风
the birds that land on your finger.
还有落在你手指上的小鸟
I think that only happens to you.
我想也就你有这造化
Lake activities are available every day until sunset,
湖边活动每天都开展到傍晚
so if you want to canoe, sail, windsurf or swim, just let me know.
所以如果你想划船, 玩帆板, 冲浪或者游泳的话, 给我说一声就行
Aren't they just the cutest?
它们真是太可爱了，不是么？
Whoa! I know I'm charming,
哇! 我知道自己魅力惊人
but you don't have to fall for me.
但你也无需为我倾倒吧
Guess I can't get too jealous, right?
我也不能太嫉妒, 对吧
After all, she isn't my Twilight.
毕竟她不是我的暮光
Not that the other Twilight was mine!
也不是说另一个暮光是我的
But, we were... you know.
但我们...你知道的
Yeah. I get it.
是啊, 我懂的
But your Twilight is a princess in Equestria,
但既然你的暮光是一位小马国的公主
hate to break it to you,
不得不给你讲的是
but that's where she's gonna spend most of her time.
她的时间主要还是得花在那边
So you're saying I just need to get over her?
你的意思是说我应该放手对吗？
Kinda, yeah.
大概是吧
Ouch. You're not pulling any punches.
唉，你可真是直接啊
Not really my style.
那可不是我的风格
Sorry.
抱歉啦
This is a safety hazard.
这是安全隐患
I suggest we close down the dock for the remainder of the camp.
我建议在露营期间最好把这个码头关了
Oh, I'm sure it won't have to be for the remainder of the camp.
哦 我觉得关闭码头那么久是没必要的
Just needs to be patched up a bit.
只是需要修补一下
I've got this!
我会搞定的!
Huh. Or maybe we do!
哈, 不如让我们来干吧
If you ask me, this whole dock needs to go.
要我说, 这整个码头都应该换掉
Building a new one could be our camp gift.
一个新的码头可以作为我们的露营礼物
Sure, it would benefit us,
这当然是为我们好
but a nice new dock would benefit future campers, too.
但是新的码头也能造福以后的露营者啊
I don't know.
我不确定
It's an awful lot of work.
这工作量可大了
I wouldn't want you guys to miss out doing other fun camp stuff,
我不想你们错过其他精彩的露营活动
because you're so busy building a dock for future campers.
来忙着给后人修一座新的码头
I hear what you're saying, Timber,
我明白你的意思，云杉
but we're Canterlot Wondercolts!
但我们可是坎特拉奇骏团
We've got a reputation to uphold!
名气摆在那里的
And there's no way we're gonna leave this place
如果我们不给这里献上一份最棒的礼物
without contributing the most awesome camp gift ever!
就不会轻易离开!
I'm with AJ, building a new dock is definitely it!
我赞同阿杰, 就修一座新码头了
What do you guys think?
你们认为呢?
Looks like it's settled, then.
看来已经定下来了啊
Looks like it.
看来是的
That's some tension alright.
看着的确不对劲
We can reinforce foundation.
我们能加固地基
Make it nice and sturdy.
修的漂亮又牢固
And we can add a wood-carved sign that says 'Camp Everfree.'
我们还能挂上一块写着“森灵营地”的木雕牌
And little boxes with food
以及小食物盒
so you can feed the ducks and fishies.
来喂鸭子喂鱼儿
Oh, we'll add lanterns so you can see at night!
哦, 再挂上灯笼在晚上照明!
Oh, it's stunning!
哦, 真是极好的
And will make an absolutely perfect runway for my camp fashion show!
这会是我营地时装秀的最佳T台!
More importantly,
重要的是
it will be a great place for docking canoes and feeding the wildlife.
这会成为停泊船只和喂养动物的好地方
Oh, you say tomato,
哦, 你是这么说
I say perfect place to showcase glamorous boho-chic stylings.
我说这是展现波西米亚嬉皮风的魅力的好地方
What do you guys think?
你们觉得怎样?
It's going to be a lot of work, but we can do it!
工程虽然浩大, 但我们能办好的!
Yes! Adult supervision!
好啊! 成人监制!
Huh, nice hammer.
哈, 不错的锤子
Where did you get it?
哪来的?
Uh, duh! The toolbox?
呃, 废话, 工具箱呗
Hah, that's cool.
哈, 不错
I made mine.
我自己做了个
Ugh.
呃
Making lanterns out of solar-powered garden lights!
用太阳能庭院灯做的灯笼
Pretty crafty there, Timber!
心灵手巧啊, 木杉!
You think that's crafty?
我这就心灵手巧了呀
You should see my macaroni art.
你应该来看看我的通心粉艺术
I'm like the Picasso of noodles.
我就像是面条界的毕加索
Alright, now!
好了, 各位!
You've made a lot of progress.
你们已经忙活了不少了
But it's going to be getting dark soon.
但太阳马上就要落山了
We can pick this up tomorrow between our other camp activities.
我们明天可以在其它的露营活动期间继续干
Everyone, get cleaned out,
大家整理好东西
and we'll gather by the fire pit at eight to share s'mores and scary stories!
我们八点会在篝火边集合, 分享果塔饼干和鬼故事
S'MORES!!!
果塔饼干!
And that's when she looked down
当她朝下看时
and realize she was wearing purple socks with a burgundy dress!
她意识到自己穿着深紫色的袜子配着紫红色的裙子!
Purple and burgundy, darlings!
深紫色和紫红色, 亲爱的
The same color family!
同一个色系啊
That was a terrifying story.
真是个可怕的故事
Yeah, I'm terrified she'll try to tell it again.
我是害怕她又讲一次
Anyone else have a spooky story?
还有谁有鬼故事要讲?
I have one.
我有一个
But I'm warning you, you might as well hug a friend now.
但我警告你们, 最好先抱上一位伙伴
That's how scary it is!
这故事就是那么可怕!
Oh, dear.
哦, 天哪
It's time I told you about the legend of Gaia Everfree.
是时候让我来告诉你们森灵盖亚的传说了
Many years ago my great-grandparents came to this forest.
很久很久以前, 我的曾祖父母来了到这个森林
Seeing its beauty, they decided that it would be the perfect place for a camp.
看到这美丽景象, 他们认为这里是修建营地的绝佳选择
But once they started building, strange things started to happen.
但当他们开始修房子时, 奇怪的事情开始发生了
One pitch-black night, when the wind was howling,
一个漆黑的夜里, 山风咆哮
a tree branch crashed through the roof of their cabin.
一棵树被吹倒在他们的房顶上
They screamed and ran outside,
他们尖叫着逃出来
only to see the giant creature rising from the earth.
只看到一只巨大的生物伏地而起
She got wild hair like the roots of a tree.
她有着树根般杂乱的头发
Her mouth had jagged rock teeth and her eyes were pools of black tar.
牙齿如参差的岩石, 眼睛如漆黑的柏油
But her aura shimmered like diamonds.
但她被宝石一样的光亮笼罩着
Anywhere she went, she left a trail of gem dust in her wake.
不论她到哪, 她都在身后留下一串宝石屑
Trembling, my great-grandparents asked who she was and what she wanted.
我的曾祖父母颤抖着问她是谁和她的意图
In a deep and hollow voice she told them that her name was Gaia Everfree –
她用深沉而空洞的声音, 告诉他们她的名字叫“森灵盖亚”
an ancient spirit who held domain over the forest,
一个守护着这片森林的古魂
and that my great-grandparents were trespassing on her land.
她说我的曾祖父母们侵入了她的领土
They begged her to let them stay and build their camp
他们乞求她允许他们在此居住并建造营地
to share this wonderful place with others.
把这片美丽的地方与他人分享
Gaia Everfree finally agreed,
森灵盖亚最终同意了
but warned them that they would not be able to keep it forever.
但是警告他们这片领土不会永远给他们
Some day she will return and reclaim the forest as her own.
总有一天她会回来收回这片属于她的森林
So if you see a trail of gem dust, you'll know that it is...
因此如果你看见一串宝石屑的话, 你就知道那是...
Gaia Everfree!
森灵盖亚!
Hey, guys! Sorry, didn't mean to scare you!
嘿伙计们! 抱歉, 我不是刻意要吓你们的
Then why did you come out of the bushes?
那你怎么从灌木丛里走出来了?
I... took the scenic route, because the forest is beautiful at night.
我...走的是观光道, 因为夜晚的森林很美丽
But no one else should do it without a guide, okay?
但没导游的情况下大家不要学我啊, 好吧?
Alright, everybody, time to head to you tents.
好了各位, 该回帐篷休息了
Oh, hey, Gloriosa.
哦, 嗨, 嘉兰
Do you have extra toothbrushes? I forgot mine.
你有多余的牙刷么? 我忘带了
Sure do! I'll get one for you.
当然有! 我会给你一个的
I'm scared of the dark! Do you have flashlights?
我怕黑! 你有手电筒吗?
Of course! I got this!
当然, 我会搞定的!
Fluttershy?
小蝶?
Sorry, Spike. I guess that story got to me.
抱歉, 斯派克, 这故事大概是吓着我了
Why? It can't be real.
为什么? 这才不是真的
I don't know.
我不知道
Gaia Everfree could be some creature that got booted from Equestria
森灵盖亚可能是从小马国驱逐出来的某种生物
and ended up in this world
然后流落到这个世界了
That's what happened with the Sirens.
塞壬们就是这样的
Eh. Sounded more like somethin' that Timber was makin' up just to scare us.
呃, 听着更像是云杉编的故事来吓我们
At least I hope it was.
至少我希望是这样的
Last thing I want is to have camp ruined by some power-crazed magical creature.
我可不想野营被某种妄图统治世界的魔法生物毁掉
Oh, hear-hear.
唉, 确实是呢
We had to deal with more than our fair share of those.
这些事情我们是遇到太多次了
At the Fall Formal, a musical showcase, the Friendship Ga–
秋季舞会, 音乐表演, 以及友谊大...
Well, I mean, you know, everything turned out alright, of course
那个, 我是说, 你知道, 事情都好起来了对吧
Mmm. I'm kinda tired. I'm in a turn in.
嗯, 我有点累了, 我先睡觉去了
Maybe lay off bringing up what happened at the Friendship Games?
还是少提起友谊大赛的事情吧?
I think she's still pretty sensitive about it.
我想她对此还是很敏感的
Our lips are sealed.
封口成功
Here I am!
我在这!
Over here.
在这
I'm always here!
我一直在这里!
No!
不!
What happened?
出什么事了?
Nothing. Sorry, Sunset.
没事, 抱歉余晖
Uh, Twilight, I think something happened.
呃, 暮光, 我想还是发生了点事
Is it time to get up already?
现在该起床了吗?
Twilight, we really have to talk about this.
暮光, 我们真的得谈谈这事了
No, we don't!
不! 不要!
Hey, I know you don't want to,
嘿, 我知道你不想谈这事
but I really think we need to figure out what's going on with your magic.
但我真的认为我们应该搞清楚你的魔法问题
If you could learn to control it–
如果你能学会如何控制它...
That's just it! I'll never be able to control it!
但这就是问题所在! 我永远控制不住的!
What happened?
发生什么了?
I didn't mean to!
我不是故意的!
We didn't see anything, so we don't know what happened.
我们什么都没看见, 所以我们也不清楚
Are you okay?
你没事吧?
Yeah. It was so weird.
没事, 真是活见鬼了
We were stuck in a middle of the lake with no wind,
我们在湖中间漂着, 一点风都没有
then all of a sudden BAM!
然后突然嘣!
The wind picked up and we were pushed right into the dock.
风猛地一吹我们就直接撞上码头了
You don't think it was the spirit, do you?!
你们不会认为是那恶灵吧?
No, it was me.
不, 是我
Spirit, show yourself!
现身吧! 恶灵
The Great and Powerful Trixie commands it!
神通广大崔克茜命令你!
What's that?!
那是什么?
Oh, man! All our hard work! Ruined!
哦天哪! 我们的成果! 都毁了!
At least the fishies are eating well.
至少鱼儿们吃得很开心
Let's salvage what we can out of the water.
我们从水里打捞一些残片补救一下吧
Maybe we can still fix this.
或许还能修好
We have to try! Camp Everfree needs our runway!
我们必须得试试! 森灵营地少不了我们的T台啊!
Dock.
是码头
Dock. Yes. That's what I meant.
码头, 是啊, 我就是这个意思
It used to be so simple
这原是小事一筹
It was a world I understood
这世界我原已参透
I didn't know what I didn't know
在我不知的那迷雾背后
And life seemed pretty good
一切都乐悠悠
But now the darkness rises
但现在黑恶涌起
From somewhere deep inside of me
在我心无底深渊里
Her power overtakes me
那魔力握我于掌心
Can I keep this midnight from getting free?
我能否封印这恶魔在心底?
If I can stay in the light
如我能沐浴晴岚
I know I'll be free
解放我自己
Then I can start to be whole
为完整自我守候
I can start to be me
我会做回自己
But instead I am struggling
然而我挣扎无止息
With all that I see
为我所见之谜
And these friends
朋友们
Mustn't see the midnight in me
愿不见我黑暗的心
The midnight in me-ee
那黑暗的心
They mustn't see the midnight in
愿不见我那黑暗的
Meeeee
心
So many squirrels.
好多松鼠啊
Spike?
斯派克?
Ah! Oh, aw man!
啊! 噢拜托!
I was having the best dream.
我正做着美梦呢
Wait, that dream could be a reality!
等等, 这个美梦可以成真啊
Before you run off to chase squirrels,
在你跑去追松鼠之前
do you have any idea where Twilight could be?
你知不知道暮光可能去了哪里?
I really need to talk to her.
我真的需要和她谈谈
What happened?
发生了什么?
Did she do that lifting things off the ground thing again?
她又把东西都弄上天了?
That's just it, I don't know if it was her,
问题就在这里, 我不知道那是不是她干的
but if it was, we need to deal with it head on.
但如果是的话, 我们必须解决它
I can track her down.
我能追踪到她
Keep it together. Deep breaths.
冷静, 深呼吸
You are not a monster.
你不是个怪物
Oh, hi.
噢, 嗨
What are you doing here?
你在这干什么呢
Uh, looking for you.
呃, 找你呢
Oh, I just went on a nature walking, got a little lost.
哦, 我只是出来散散步, 但是有点迷路了
Let me show you the way.
我来带路吧
I'm kind of an expert at these woods.
我对这片树林可是很熟悉了
I've lived here my whole life.
自从出生我就一直住在这里
That must have been nice.
在一个营地长大
Growing up at a camp.
一定很有意思
Yeah, though it has its downsides.
是啊, 尽管也有些不好的方面
When I was younger I wished we'd sell this place
在我年纪更小的时候, 我曾希望我们能卖了这地方
so we can live in a town like normal people.
让我们能像一般人一样在城镇生活
Really?
真的?
I was ten. I really wanted to hang out in the mall.
那时我才 10 岁, 我特别想去商业街玩
I've never told that to anyone.
我还没有把这话给其他人说过
You must be special.
你一定很特别
And not just because you have tree branch in your hair.
而且不只是因为你头发里插着根树枝
Uh. How long has that been in there?
呃, 它插在那里多久了
Not long. Just the whole time we were talking.
不久吧, 就我们聊天的这一会儿
Then why didn't you say something?
那你怎么什么都不说
I guess we can help Twilight deal with the magic stuff a little later.
我想我们可以晚点再帮暮光解决魔法问题
Rock climbing is all about perseverance and trust.
攀岩的关键在于坚持和信任
Rarity, you can trust that Applejack will spot you.
瑞瑞, 你要相信阿杰能拉住你
Yeah, so you can totally go faster than you're going.
对, 所以你完全可以爬得更快一点
Rainbow Dash!
云宝黛西!
Sorry. I've been waiting to do this since we got here.
抱歉, 我从到这里之后就一直等着攀岩呢
Well, you have to wait a little longer, darling.
你还得再多等一小会儿, 亲爱的
Oh, good!
哦, 太好了
Twilight, if you spot me, I can finally go.
暮光, 如果你能拉住我, 我就能爬了
I'll go get another harness.
我再去找套安全带
I'm not sure–
我不是很确－
I'll better make sure my sister doesn't need anything.
我最好去看看我姐姐有没有什么事
See you later.
稍后再见喽?
Twilight, there you are!
暮光, 你在这里啊
I was looking for you!
我正在找你呢
Was that an earthquake?
地震了吗?
We aren't near any fault lines.
我们可不在任何断裂带附近
Hey! Who left this crystally dusty stuff here?!
嘿! 谁把这些亮闪闪的粉末撒在这里了?
I-I believe I'd like to come down now!
我——我想我最好还是下来吧
Sorry, it's a little bit stuck.
抱歉, 绳子有点卡住了
Applejack! What are you doing?!
阿杰! 你在干什么!?
Is everything okay over there?
一切都还好吗?
Uh, I don't know what happened.
呃, 我不知道发生了什么
I didn't even pull the rope that hard.
我没有那么大力地拉绳子啊
It's like she was light as a feather all of sudden.
就好像她突然变得轻如鸿毛了
I was scared half to death!
我差点被吓死
It wasn't my fault! Let me help you get your harness out.
这不是我的错! 让我来帮你把安全带解开吧
No, thank you!
不用, 谢谢!
What in the world just happened?!
刚刚到底发生了什么!?
Oh, dear! I am so sorry! I think.
噢天哪! 真抱歉!
Did I just do... whatever that was?
刚才那……是我干的?
I don't think it was your fault.
我不觉得那是你的错
I need go get Applejack a towel.
我得去给阿杰找条毛巾
Me too.
我一起去
You're not the only one with a new kind of magic!
你不是唯一一个有了新魔法的人
This is great!
这太棒了
No, it's not!
不, 并不棒!
Rarity and Applejack could've really hurt each other!
瑞瑞和阿杰差点就真的弄伤了对方
Why is this happening? I don't–
到底为什么会发生这一切 我不—
Hi, girls! Anything I can do for you?
嗨两位! 我能为你们做些什么?
Uh, Applejack just fell into the lake!
呃, 阿杰刚刚跌进湖里了
Oh, no!
哦不
She's gonna need warm towels, dry clothes, oh, and a hot cocoa!
她需要热毛巾、干衣服, 噢, 还有热可可
I've got this!
我会搞定的!
Fluttershy?
小蝶?
What happened?!
出什么事了?!
I don't know, we were just decorating cookies and–
我也不知道, 刚刚我们正在装饰饼干, 然后—
And I was all
然后我就像这样
"You need more sprinkles! And you need more sprinkles!"
“你再来点糖粉! 你也再来点糖粉! ”
So, standard Pinkie Pie stuff.
所以, 标准的萍琪式套路
I was just tossing sprinkles to Fluttershy,
就在刚才我把糖粉扔向小蝶的时候
when all of a sudden they glowed pink and exploded!
它们突然闪起了粉光然后就炸开了!
Just like that, only earlier!
刚才就是这样的!
Oookaay, why don't you lay off touching stuff for a while?
所以, 你还是暂时不要碰这些东西了好吧?
Oh, dear. We really should clean all of this up.
噢天啊, 我们应该尽快把这里收拾一下
Can someone help me out?
谁能帮我一下?
Thank you, mister bird.
谢谢你, 鸟先生
Why, of course I can get you little something to–
我当然可以给你一些—
Did you just... talk?
你刚才…说话了?
But I don't speak "chirp".
但是我不会说鸟语啊
I don't know if you're the only bird I can understand.
我不确定我是不是只能和你交流
Oh, no!
噢别!
Please don't call for your friends.
请不要叫你的朋友们过来
It's nice to meet all of you, too.
也很高兴见到你们
Were you just talking to the birds?
你刚才在跟鸟说话?
Um, yes?
好像, 是的?
Did you tell them what happened?
你告诉她们刚刚发生了什么吗?
So crazy!
简直疯了!
I hoisted up Rarity up the rock climbin' wall like it was nothing!
我一下子就把瑞瑞拉到了攀岩墙顶端
Like I had way more strength than I usually do.
好像我的力气一下子比往常大了许多
And I made diamondy thing appear out of nowhere, which normally I'd be excited about.
我还凭空变出了一个钻石般的东西, 如果是平常我肯定会高兴坏了
I mean, the facets were just perfect. And the–
我是说, 那切面简直完美, 而且——
Rarity!
瑞瑞!
Oh, sorry.
哦, 抱歉
It knocked Applejack over and then it disappeared!
那个东西撞到了阿杰, 然后就消失了!
Speaking of disappearin', has anybody seen Rainbow Dash?
说到消失, 你们有谁看见云宝黛茜了吗?
Ow!
嗷!
Whoa! How did you do that?
喔! 你怎么做到的?
I don't know.
我也不知道
I've started running to get the harness
我刚才准备跑去拿安全带
and the next thing I knew I was practically back in town!
结果下一刻就发现我已经跑回城里去了!
But if you had some sort of superspeed
但是如果你有这样的能力的话
why you were gone for so long?
为什么这么久你才回来?
Because I lost it when I got far away.
因为我跑远了之后能力就消失了
And then it came back when got close to camp.
但当我一靠近营地时它又出现了
Being at camp is giving us all new magical abilities!
这个营地给了我们所有人神奇的新魔法!
Not all of us has gotten new abilities.
并不是所有人都获得了新魔法
I haven't, but Twilight– hasn't, either.
我就没有, 不过暮光——也没有
So much for my theory
看来我那个离坎高远一点
that leaving CHS would mean leaving any new magic business behind.
就能摆脱这些魔法玩意的说法都是白扯了
Something at the camp must be making this happen.
一定是营地里的某些东西导致了这些事情的发生
Um, Gaia Everfree?
呃, 森灵盖亚?
Applejack! I was looking for you!
阿杰! 我正找你呢!
Here, I brought you some towels and dry clothes.
这里, 我给你带了一些毛巾和干衣服
Uh, what happened in here?
呃, 这里发生了什么?
We're kinda trying to figure that out.
我们也想知道呢
Well, don't worry about it. I've got this!
好吧, 别担心, 我会搞定的!
Gloriosa, I kicked my beanbag into the lake!
嘉兰! 我不小心把豆袋踢进湖里去了!
I'll get you another one!
我会给你一袋新的!
And I'm all out of arrows!
还有我的箭也不够了!
Say no more! New arrows coming right up!
别急! 新的箭马上就来!
There you are!
你在这里!
Filthy Rich is back.
臭钱回来了
Do you want me to handle it?
你需要我去应付他吗?
Absolutely not! I got this!
当然不! 我会搞定的!
Fluttershy, enough with the screaming!
小蝶, 不要再尖叫了好吗!
I didn't scream.
不是我叫的
For once.
也就这次
Nobody did.
没人叫啊
Huh?
啊?
Attention, campers!
营员们请注意!
Anyone who's interested in making floating paper lanterns
所有想要制作天灯的营员
please meet us by the picnic tables.
请到野餐桌集合
I don't know about the rest of y'all,
我不知道你们怎么想
but I've been lookin' forward to comin' here for a month.
我可是期待这次露营好久了
Maybe we forget about this new magic for a bit
也许我们应该把这些个魔法暂时抛在脑后
and just try to focus on enjoyin' our time at camp?
然后好好专注于享受我们的营地时光?
I was oh, so excited about the designs I've come up with the camp fashion show.
我也在为给我的营地时装秀做设计忙得正酣呢
And I've barely gotten to whoop anybody in tetherball.
我玩绳球还没玩痛快呢
I think we should try to figure it out.
我觉得我们应该查个清楚
But if letting it go for now is what the rest of you want...
不过如果你们想先暂时忽略它的话……
Um, Pinkie Pie, what are you doing?
呃, 萍琪派, 你在干嘛?
Putting marshmallows in my lantern.
往我的天灯里粘棉花糖呀
Then when we light them, mine will be beautiful and delicious!
我们点燃天灯以后, 我做的一定又好看又好吃!
Hey, Twilight, why aren't you with everyone else?
嘿, 暮光, 你为什么不和其他人呆在一起?
Sunset said something at camp is causing the other girls to get new magic.
余晖说营地里有什么东西让其他女生也获得了魔法
I think it's Midnight Sparkle.
我觉得是午夜闪闪做的好事
She's still part of me.
她还是我的一部分
I can feel it.
我能感觉到
And I think her magic is infecting my friends.
而且我觉得是她的魔法在影响我的朋友们
What are we gonna do?
我们该怎么做啊?
I don't know what I can do.
我不知道我能够做些什么
Okay, everyone!
好了各位
It's time to watch your lanterns fly!
是时候放飞你们的天灯了!
Hey, cool lantern!
嘿, 好酷的灯笼
Mine's my face.
我画的是我的脸
Uh, you okay?
呃, 你还好吗?
Mhm.
嗯哼
You don't seem like yourself tonight.
你今天晚上看起来不太正常
Ready?
准备好了吗?
And... go!
现在……放!
Aw! Oh well!
嗷! 噢好吧
Now I get to eat it!
现在我要吃了它!
Yep, beautiful and delicious.
没错, 好看又好吃
Twilight?
暮光?
Twilight!
暮光!
Oh, where is she going?
噢, 她去哪了?
Twilight?
暮光?
What are you doing out here?
你在这里做什么?
We're... we're meeting a cab to take us home.
我们……我们想打车回家
She thought you'd talk her out of it.
她觉得你会带她回去
Because I would.
因为我的确会
Twilight, you can't leave.
暮光, 你不能走
You don't think it was the spirit, do you?!
你们不会认为是那恶灵吧?
No, it was me.
不, 是我
I think it's Midnight Sparkle.
我觉得是午夜闪闪做的好事
She's still part of me.
她还是我的一部分
I can feel it.
我能感觉到
And I think her magic is infecting my friends.
而且我觉得是她的魔法在影响我的朋友们
Twilight, there's no Midnight Sparkle.
暮光, 午夜闪闪不存在
There's only you.
你只是你自己而已
How did you know what I was thinking?
你是怎么知道我在想些什么的?
When I touched your hand, I can see things.
当我握住你的手时, 我能看到一些东西
I can understand why you were leaving.
我能理解你为什么想要离开
My new magic!
我的新魔法!
This is my new magic!
这是我的新魔法!
This is incredible!
太神奇了!
No, it's not.
不, 不
I'm infecting you now!
现在我也影响你了!
Twilight, you have to stop looking at this as a bad thing.
暮光, 你不能再认为这是一件坏事了
Easy for you to say.
你说出来倒是轻巧
Magic turned you into something beautiful.
魔法让你变得光彩照人
The last time I tried to use it,
但我上一次使用的时候
it turned me into a monster.
它却把我变成了一个怪物
I'm just so afraid it's gonna happen again.
我只是害怕这种事会再次发生
Yes, last time I turned into something amazing,
是啊, 上一次魔法把我变得十分夺目
but I've let magic turn me into a monster, too.
但是我也曾经让魔法变成过怪物
So if anyone understands what you're going through, it's me.
所以如果有谁能理解你的话, 那就是我了
I can help you, Twilight.
我能帮你, 暮光
And the rest of our friends can be there for you, too.
我们的其他朋友也会一直在你身边
But not if you run away.
但前提是你不能逃避
I'll stay.
我会留下的
I still don't think this is a good idea for me
但我还是觉得此时我离我们其他朋友太近
to be near the rest of our friends right now.
不是个好主意
Not until we know why this is happening.
起码我们应该先弄清楚原因是什么
Understood.
明白
What was that?
那是什么?
Wait. Twilight?
等等, 暮光?
Timber?
云杉?
I'm so glad it's just you!
真高兴原来只是你！
Wait, what are you doing out here?
等等, 你来这里干嘛?
With an axe.
还带着斧子
I was chopping down firewood.
我在劈柴
In the middle of the night?
大半夜劈柴?
We needed more for tomorrow's campfire.
我们需要为明晚的篝火晚会做准备啊
And if I didn't take care of it tonight,
如果今晚不准备好的话
it would be one more thing Gloriosa would add to her list.
嘉兰就要多忙活好久呢
I've got this!
我会搞定的!
What about you two?
你们俩呢?
Why are you hanging out in the woods in the middle of the night?
你们大晚上的在森林里闲逛什么呢?
Oh, I was sleepwalking.
噢, 我在梦游
Twilight found me and was bringing me back to camp.
暮光找到我了, 正想把我带回营地
Mhm.
嗯
Come on, I'll walk you guys back.
来吧, 我带你们回去
I'll protect you from Gaia Everfree!
我来保护你们以免遇到森灵盖亚!
Everfree! Everfree!
森灵盖亚! 森灵盖亚!
Come on,
拜托
that's obviously just a spooky story you made up to tell around the campfire.
这显然就是你编出来的篝火晚会鬼故事嘛
Oh, no.
噢, 不
It's legit.
是真的
How else would you explain what happened at the docks?
不然你怎么解释发生在码头的事情?
And that weird thing when the earth shook?
还有地震的时候发生的那些怪事?
Uh, come on, I know a shortcut back to the tents.
来吧, 我知道一条回营地的近路
Legit, huh?
真的, 哈?
I think we just found our Gaia Everfree.
我想我们刚刚找到我们的森灵盖亚了
But why would he work so hard to make us think she was real?
但他为什么非要让我们觉得她是真的呢?
You heard what he said
你也听到他说
about wishing his sister would sell this camp.
希望他姐姐卖掉这座营地的那些话了
If nobody wants to come here,
如果能因为这里有愤怒的古代自然之神什么的东西
because it's home to some angry ancient nature spirit,
而让人们不再来到这座营地的话
it sure would help his cause.
就能帮助他的愿望成真了
We should tell Twilight.
我们应该告诉暮光
Not yet.
先别
She's obviously going through a lot right now.
显然现在她担心的事情已经够多的了
We should probably be a hundred percent sure
在我们没有百分百确定她喜欢的人
before we tell her the guy she likes is a jerk
是个想把所有人从营地吓跑的混蛋之前
who's trying to run everybody out of camp.
还是先不要告诉她吧
Uh-huh!
嗯哼
Phew!
呼!
Uh, you gonna give us a hand here, Rarity?
呃, 你不来搭把手吗, 瑞瑞?
Oh, I'd love to,
噢, 我当然愿意啦
but I really need to get the stitching on this poncho done
但是我必须先把这个披风缝好
before it's going to make it into the camp fashion show.
不然就没法用在营地里的时装秀上
Though at the pace you two are moving.
不过看你们俩移动的速度
I don't know that the runway will ever be finished.
我都不知道这 T 台能不能做得完
The dock is our gift to the camp
这码头是咱们送给营地的礼物
and it's gonna get finished.
我们一定会造好它
That is if Rainbow Dash would hurry up and bring me more wood.
前提是云宝能赶快帮我把木料搬过来
Oh, I can't go any faster!
噢, 我已经不能再快了好吧!
I don't want to end up in the woods again.
我不想再跑进森林里
Don't be silly.
别傻了
Really?
是嘛?
I know I said we should try to forget all about this new magic business,
我知道我说过我们应该尽量忘掉这些新魔法什么的
but I can't.
但是没办法
What if I hammer the board into splinters?
要是我把板子锤成了碎块呢?
Aw, shoot!
噢, 倒霉
I'm all out of nails.
我没钉子了
Oh, here you go!
噢, 接好了!
Pinkie, no!
萍琪, 别!
What?
怎么?
Oh, did you think that nails would explode like the sprinkles?
噢, 你们觉得这钉子会像糖粉一样爆炸吗?
Wow! Glad that didn't happen, huh?
哇哦, 没爆炸真好, 哈?
Sorry, girls.
抱歉, 姑娘们
I didn't mean to
我不是有意的
And I don't know how to control this.
我也不知道该怎么控制这个魔法
It's okay.
没关系啦
Oh, none of us do.
噢, 我们都不知道的
Which is why we shouldn't pretend this isn't happening.
这就是为什么我们不能无视它
Do you have them now, too?
你现在也有魔法了吗?
It started last night.
昨晚发现的
When I touch people,
当我接触其他人的时候
it's like I can feel what they're feeling and see their memories.
我似乎能够看到别人的想法和记忆
Oooh, fancy! Try me, try me!
喔, 有趣! 看看我的, 看看我的!
Lalalala. Ooh, taffy!
啦啦啦, 噢, 太妃糖!
That explains so much.
这解释了很多
Yep.
是啊
Girls, we can't just brush these powers aside,
姑娘们, 我们不能仅仅因为这不是获得这些能力的好时候
because it doesn't seem like the ideal time to get them.
而就那么把它们置之不理
What if it turns out that they could actually make things better?
要是能利用它们让事情变得更加顺利呢?
So you have magic
你拥有魔力
And it's not that great
却没那么美
But when it found you
但邂逅之时
You know it was fate
方知命运所为
And it might seem scary now
现在看似可怕
But it can be wonderful, too
但它也能光彩炫目
So, how about we embrace the magic
所以一起拥抱魔力
And make the magic part of you
让这魔力来成就你
You take a little dash of magic
用上一点点的魔力
And you let it ignite
让它放出光彩
Mix things up a little bit
也许轻轻混合起
And it might start to go right
柳暗花明就会来
In just five seconds flat
在转瞬几秒里
How the story has changed
故事如此变换
All cause now you've embraced the magic
只因为你拥抱了魔力
And it just got better in every way
一切都渐入佳境
I say embrace the magic
让我们拥抱魔力
No more holding back, just let it out
不再压抑尽情去释放
If you can take the magic
若你能拥有魔力
And learn a little more what it can do
并学会掌握它神奇力量
Once the magic is part of you
让这魔力成就你
What's standing in your way
什么在拖后腿
That you can't move today?
让你无法去追?
You've got the strength in you
你已拥有力量
To make your dreams come true
去实现你梦想
No need to shield yourself
不必遮掩自我
From the magic that can help
用已注定的魔法
Protect from any harm that might come
保护自己免遭未卜之伤
So you have magic
你拥有魔力
And it's not that great
却没那么美
But when it found you
但邂逅之时
You know it was fate
方知命运所为
So, if you listen close
所以就去倾听
You might make a new friend
就能交到朋友
And together we can make it!
齐心协力定能胜利!
I say embrace the magic
让我们拥抱魔力
No more holding back, just let it out
不再压抑尽情去释放
If you can take the magic
若你能拥有魔力
And learn a little more what it can do
就学会掌握它神奇力量
Once the magic is part of you
让这魔力成就你
Okay, that was pretty awesome!
不错, 这确实很酷炫
And look what you managed to accomplish!
再看看你们的成果
Please, please, please
拜托, 拜托, 拜托
can we do a run-through for the fashion show on it right this minute?
我们能现在就在这里做一次时装秀彩排吗?
Thought you weren't finished with the stitching on your poncho.
可是你的披风都还没缝好
I am now.
现在缝好了
Get started without me.
你们先开始吧
I've gotta go find Twilight.
我得去找下暮光
Seeing what we've been able to do here might make her embrace the new magic, too!
说不定她在看到我们的成果后也能坦然面对这新的魔法了
Uh, not that she has any.
呃, 不过她也没有
I just wish you didn't tell them that ridiculous story!
我真希望你没给他们讲过那个蠢故事
Ah, this is all too much for you!
啊, 这对你来说压力太大了!
You have to let it go!
你得学会放手!
I knew it!
我就知道!
He wants her to get rid of the camp!
他想让她卖掉营地!
Ugh!
啊!
Sunset Shimmer?
余晖烁烁?
What were you doing behind that door?
你在门后面干什么呢?
What?
啥?
Um, nothing!
啊, 没什么
I, um, lost an earring. Uh, there it is!
我——那个——耳环掉了, 哈, 找到了
Hey, listen.
嘿, 那个
I'm glad I ran into you.
很高兴正好碰到你
I really wanted to thank you.
我很想谢谢你
For what?
谢什么?
For the tough love.
谢你的心慈口辣
Telling me I should get over Twilight.
告诉我我应该放下对暮光的感情
I needed to hear that.
这对我帮助很大
Sure, no problem.
啊, 不客气
Is something wrong?
有什么不对的吗?
What?
啥?
No. Why?
没事啊?
Come on, Sunset.
别装了, 余晖
We used to date.
我们在一起过
I know when something's bothering you.
我能看出来你在烦恼些什么
Okay, here's the deal.
好吧, 是这样的
My friend really likes someone
我的一个朋友喜欢上了一个人
but I don't think that someone is who she thinks they are.
但是我觉得那个人的本性和我朋友心里的形象完全不同
I don't wanna upset my friend by telling her what I think
我怕告诉了她我的想法会让她心烦
because I also want to protect her
但因为我又想保护她
because if what I think is happening is really happening
因为如果事情真如我所想的话
then she deserves to know.
她还是应该知道
You know?
懂了么?
Nnnno.
完全不懂
But what I do know is that your friend is lucky
但是我知道能有你这样替人分忧的朋友
to have someone like you to look out for them.
你的朋友们是相当的幸运
Really?
真的?
Yeah.
是啊
You know, you've changed a lot since we went out.
当初我们一起的时候你还不是这样呢
You're so much... nicer.
现在的你…更好了
Thanks. I'm glad you noticed.
谢了, 真高兴你看出来了
Uh, look, maybe you and me
那个, 也许我们能……
we could start over as... friends.
重新开始…从朋友做起?
Uh, uh, sounds great.
嗯嗯, 听起来不错
I gotta go!
我先走了
Cool, yeah!
酷, 耶!
I want to start over later, too!
我也觉得现在重新开始太早了
Ah, shoot!
哦, 该死!
He's definitely up to something!
他绝对在密谋着什么
It's Sunset.
是余晖
She says to meet her by the rock quarry.
她说去采石场见她
I thought we weren't supposed to hike out that far.
我们不是不能进入那地方吗?
She says it's important!
她说有很重要的事
What is that?
那是什么?
Shhh!
嘘!
What's going on down there?
那里出什么事了?
I think it's Gaia Everfree.
我觉得是森灵盖亚
Or rather someone who wants us to think she's back.
或者说是某个希望我们认为她回归了的人
C'mon!
走!
Whoa...
哇…
This place is beautiful.
这里真漂亮
There's Equestrian magic here.
这里有小马国的魔力
I can... I can feel it.
我能……我能感觉得到
Wait.
等等
I thought Timber was just faking there was a magical nature creature.
我还以为魔法生物什么的都是云杉棕木捏造出来的
Are you saying it's real?
现在你的意思是真的有?
Timber?
云杉?
What does he have to do with any of this?
他又是怎么和这事扯上关系的?
Nothing.
没关系
It's all me.
都是我干的
Gloriosa?
嘉兰?
But... Timber.
可是……云杉
I was sure he was the one
我还以为是他
trying to make it seem like Gaia Everfree was back.
想让大家觉得森灵盖亚回来了
It was you who was trying to scare everyone away?
原来是你想吓跑大家?
I would never try to scare anyone away from Camp Everfree.
我可不想吓跑森灵营地的任何一个人
My, oh my.
哎呀呀
You fell behind on your payments, Gloriosa.
看来你贷款还慢了啊, 嘉兰
I own the land now.
现在这块地是我的了
Please, my great-grandparents founded this place.
求你了, 这里是我曾祖父母创建
It's been in our family for generations!
并一代一代传下来的
You have to let the camp stay!
你不能把营地拆了!
Instead of turning it into a spa resort
也不能把这里变成一个水疗度假村
that will line my pockets with more money than this camp ever could?
然后赚到像这种小营地永远都赚不到的大把钞票?
I don't think so.
我可不这么想
Please!
求您了!
I-I-I-I just need a little more time!
我－我－我－我只是需要一点时间!
Fine. I'll give you 'til the end of the month.
也行, 这个月底就是最后的期限
Humph.
哼
What'll I do?
我该怎么办?
Huh?
哈?
Oof.
噢
Wow!
哇哦!
You don't know what those things are!
你不了解这些东西
But I know what they can do!
但是我知道它们能做些什么!
I've been practicing!
我一直都在练习!
I can control their power now!
现在我已经能控制它们的力量了!
You don't know that for sure!
你又没有把握!
This is our camp, and it's being taken away!
我们的营地都要没了!
If this has to be our last week here
如果这是我们在这里度过的最后一周
I'm going to use whatever it takes to make it count!
那我就要不惜一切代价办好这一次
You were using magic all over the place!
你到处使用魔法
I had to tell them something to cover for you!
我总得跟他们说点什么幌子吧?
What did you want me to do?!
你还希望我怎么办?
I just wish you didn't tell them that ridiculous story!
我真希望你没给他们讲过这个蠢故事
Ah, this is all too much for you!
啊, 这对你来说压力太大了!
You have to let it go!
你得学会放手!
Timber wasn't talking about letting go of the camp.
云杉说的放手不是放弃营地
He was talking about you letting go of the magical geodes!
是说要你放弃这些魔法晶簇
All those things you were doing to make this week the best week ever.
你一直试着让这周变成最棒露营周
Every time you used magic to do them
但你每次使用魔法
you caused another problem somewhere else!
就又会导致出新的问题
Timber was... covering for you!
云杉是在……为你打掩护!
How do you know what I was doing with the geodes?
你怎么知道我在用这些晶簇?
How do you know about the magic?
你怎么知道魔法的事情的?
I can see things.
我能看到
Feel things.
我能感觉到
Because I have magic, too.
因为我也有魔法
And so does she.
而且她也有
And so do our friends.
我们的朋友们都有
Gloriosa, Timber wasn't wrong.
嘉兰, 云杉说的没错
Maybe you should stop using magic?
也许你不应该再使用魔法了?
Too much of it can be dangerous if you can't control it!
强大的魔法若是控制不当是会很危险的
Oh, I got this!
我会搞定的!
And I'm going to use it to save my camp.
我要用魔法拯救我的营地
I just need more power!
我只是需要更多力量!
No!
不要!
Sorry, girls.
抱歉了, 两位
I know what I need to do.
我很清楚自己要做什么
But I feel like we're not on the same page.
不过看起来你们两个并不理解我
So...
所以……
Gloriosa!
嘉兰!
No!
不!
Where are Twilight and Sunset?
暮光和余晖呢?
They're missing our dress rehearsal.
她们要错过我们的彩排了
Uh-uh.
嗯哼
I suppose we can get started without them.
还是不等她们了
Whenever you're ready!
准备好就开始吧!
Hmm, Told you you'd like it.
都说过你会喜欢的
It's alright... I guess.
我看……还行吧
I do get to keep it after camp though, right?
露营完了我就可以拿走了, 对吗?
She looks... different.
她看起来……变了
Yeah. She looks... taller.
是啊, 她看起来……变高了
This is only a preview.
这只是预展而已
I've got another entire line I'll debut at the real thing.
正式出演的时候我还有另外整整一系列要上呢
Why did you stop the–
你把音乐停了干－
Oh my goodness!
我的天啊
Attention, campers!
营员们, 注意!
It's Gaia Everfree!
是森灵盖亚
She's real!
她是真的!
Aah! We're doomed!
啊! 我们完蛋啦!
Gloriosa?!
嘉兰?!
What are you doing?!
你在干什么?!
That's Gloriosa?
那是嘉兰?
Am I going crazy or are her feet not touching the ground?
是我疯了还是她真的飘起来了?
Freaky-deaky!
我怕怕!
I have an announcement to make!
我要宣布一件事!
Filthy Rich wants this to be the last session of Camp Everfree.
臭钱想要让这次变成森灵营地的最后一次露营
But don't worry
但是不要担心
I got this!
我会搞定的!
Oh, come on!
有没有搞错!
We literally just finished building that!
我们才建好的!
I have waited for the day
守候于此天昏黑
To send this greedy wolf away
誓要驱逐贪狼回
Now the magic is my salvation
神秘的魔法助我为神
Gather close in my protection
雄伟缭绕据于我身
We will stand for Everfree!
定要守护这营地!
Behold the beauty of nature in all its glory
仰慕那自然的恩赐  荣美而华丽
No need to fear the vultures at the door
不惧那贪婪之人眉睫翘
Right here you have me to protect you
我会守护你战至最后
Within these walls of thorns
于荆之壁怒吼
For Everfree for evermore!
为森灵地永不沦落!
They have come into our domain
前方的战火燃我眉
Here to seal our camp in chains
铁链之下吾土危
But we have held it for generations
但我们守护它代代至深
This is just a complication
混乱只不过是须臾之时
We will stand for Everfree!
定要保卫这营地!
Trust in me, this is for your own good
相信我  一切不会辜负
Don't be afraid
不要颤巍
Nature is our friend
自然伴吾身
All of this beauty that surrounds us
围绕我们不止美丽繁华
Every lovely bloom designed to defend
花朵的美丽  是自卫的伪装
Let them come! Just let them try!
来啊放马都过来!
I'm not about to say goodbye!
我不会轻易退下来!
This camp will be here throughout the ages
营地将会于此永驻万世
Written into the history pages
被世界纪录于广阔历史
We will stand for Everfree!
定要保卫这营地!
Oh, why do these kinds of things always happen to us?
为什么这种事总是发生在我们身上啊?
What are we going to do?
我们现在该怎么办啊?
What we always do!
干我们的老本行啊!
Save the day!
拯救大家!
Oh boy, oh boy, oh boy!
天哪, 天哪, 天哪!
This is gonna be so much fun!
这一定会非常好玩的!
Oh! I only wish we had time to make superhero capes!
我真希望我们能抽点儿时间去做几件超级英雄披风!
Oh, me too!
加我一个!
Enough about our wardrobe!
别再聊那些穿的东西了!
We've got to stop Gloriosa from trapping everybody in here!
我们还得阻止嘉兰把大家困在营地里呢!
Um, hi.
呃, 嗨
Do you think you can give us a hand–
你们能否帮我们一把……
Um, er, paw? We could really use a way out.
呃, 一爪? 我们真的很需要一条能出去的路
This isn't working!
没有用!
Her magic is too strong!
她的魔法太强大了!
Nice work, Spike!
干得好, 斯派克!
Twilight, you have to use your magic!
暮光, 你必须使用你的魔法!
I don't think I can lift something that big.
我不觉得我能搬得动这么大的东西
It's our only chance of getting out of here
这是我们能帮助朋友们
and helping our friends!
并逃离这里的唯一可能啊!
Why are you fighting me?
为何你们都要跟我作对?
I'm doing this to save our camp!
我可是在拯救我们的营地啊!
I'm doing this for you!
我可是为了你们好!
Gloriosa, let's just think about this for a moment, shall we?
嘉兰, 我们来稍微讨论下这事如何?
I mean, I think Camp Everfree is absolutely delightful
我是说, 森灵营地的确非常棒
but I just don't know that I'm quite ready to give up my weekly trips to the spa.
但我不知道我是否准备好放弃享受我每周一次的水疗了
To the spa.
享受水疗?
TO THE SPA?!
享受水疗?!
Gloriosa, this isn't the way!
嘉兰, 这样不是办法啊!
I appreciate your concern, Timber
我很感谢你的关心, 云杉
BUT I GOT THIS!
但是我会搞定的!
No, you don't!
不, 不行啊!
Twilight, do you think you can use your magic?
暮光, 你能使用你的魔法吗?
I don't wanna use too much.
我不想过度使用
Midnight Sparkle could take over.
午夜闪闪可能会控制我
Twilight, our friends are in there!
暮光, 我们的朋友都在里面啊!
Okay.
好吧
Please, Gloriosa.
嘉兰, 拜托
What you're doing is crazy.
你的所作所为简直太疯狂了
You have to listen to me!
你一定得听我说啊!
That isn't Gloriosa.
那不是嘉兰
Twilight!
暮光!
Sunset!
余晖!
You're okay!
你们没事!
That isn't your sister.
那不是你姐姐
It's someone who's been consumed by Equestrian magic.
那只是个被小马国魔法吞噬的人而已
Whoever you are, you have to let my sister go!
不管你是谁, 快把我姐姐还回来!
Please, Gloriosa, come back!
拜托, 嘉兰, 快点回来!
I need you!
我需要你!
Gloriosa!
嘉兰!
Rarity!
瑞瑞!
I can't keep this up forever!
我没办法永远挡住这些荆棘!
It's up to you.
看你的了
You can use your magic to pull the brambles apart!
你可以用你的魔法扯断这些荆棘!
No. There's too many of them.
不行, 这太多了
It would take too much magic. I can't!
我做不到! 这会消耗太多魔法了!
It's the only way!
这是唯一的办法了!
You have to embrace the magic inside you!
你得接纳你的魔法
What if she takes over?
万一她控制了我呢?
What if instead of saving everyone
万一我变成了午夜闪闪
I turn into Midnight Sparkle and only make things worse?
不仅没能救到我们反而让事情变得雪上加霜了呢?
That won't happen!
那不会发生的!
We won't let it.
我们不会让它发生的
Come on, Twilight!
来吧, 暮光!
You have to be stronger than she is!
你得要比她更强大!
You will never control me! I will always be a part of you!
你永远无法掌控我! 我永远是你的一部分!
Nooo!
不要!
Twilight, listen to me! You are in charge!
暮光, 听我说! 你才是控制的人!
You are a light, darling! A force for good!
你是一道光, 亲爱的! 你是正义的力量!
Yeah! You can kick the darkness's butt!
对! 你能赶走黑暗势力的!
We're here for you, Twilight!
我们支持你, 暮光!
And we'll be here no matter what!
而且我们无论如何都会在你身边!
We believe in you!
我们相信你!
You are not Midnight Sparkle!
你不是午夜闪闪!
No! I am Twilight Sparkle!
没错! 我是暮光闪闪!
And the magic I carry inside me is... the Magic of Friendship!
而且我心中的魔法……是友谊的魔法!
No! Stop!
不! 住手!
Gloriosa?
嘉兰?
What... What happened?
发……发生了什么事?
It's okay.
没事了
It's gonna be okay.
已经没事了
You did it!
你做到了!
Oh, nice bling.
喔, 光泽不错
What... What are these?
这些……东西到底是啥?
I'm not sure.
我不知道
But clearly we have some kind of connection to them.
但显然的我们跟这些东西有着某种联系
I almost don't care what they are.
我才不管这些东西是什么呢
They are gorgeous!
它们看起来超漂亮!
And will totally go with the other collection I was working on for the camp fashion show!
而且和我为了营地时装秀而做出的其他作品很搭!
That's probably cancelled, isn't it?
不过时装秀应该已经被取消了, 对吧?
I am so sorry.
我真的很抱歉
I only wanted this to be the best week Camp Everfree has ever had.
我只是想要让大家有个史上最棒的露营周
Then instead I've made it the worst.
结果我却搞砸了一切
Maybe it's for the best that I'm losing the camp to Filthy Rich.
或许让臭钱接手营地才是最好的选择
No, it's not.
不, 并不是
This camp has meant so much to so many people
这个营地对很多人来说都很重要
my sister and me included.
包括了我和我的妹妹
Why do you think we wanted our students to come here?
不然你认为我们为什么会选择带我们的学生来到这里
We can't let Filthy Rich take this place away!
我们不能让臭钱夺走这座营地!
If camp meant so much to you two
如果这营地对你们姐弟俩很重要
maybe it meant as much to the other campers who came here in years past.
或许也对历年以来在这里露营的其他营员们一样重要
And maybe we can get them to help save it!
也许我们能让他们帮忙一起来拯救营地!
Oh! Like a fundraiser?
哦, 像是办场募捐活动?
Or a ball?!
或是办场舞会?!
Our band could play!
我们乐队可以表演!
I can help writing a new song just for the occasion!
我可以帮忙专门写首新歌!
Those are all good ideas, but where would we hold it?
这些的确都是好主意, 但我们该在哪里举办?
We can hold it in the crystal cave!
我们可以办在水晶洞穴里!
A Crystal Ball! I'm on it!
一场水晶舞会! 我这就去办!
I admire everyone's enthusiasm.
我很感谢大家的热情相助
Really, I do.
真的
But I-I just don't know how we're going to plan a ball by tomorrow
但我——我不知道要怎么才能赶在明天前筹备好一场舞会
and invite everyone.
并邀请大家都来参加
We got this!
我们会搞定的!
I used to think that stories were just that
我曾认为命运已注定
Set in stone, concrete as a fact
铁了心再无变革的余地
It didn't dawn on me
我那时不知悉
That I could change history
我会创造这奇迹
Now I know I'm writing my own song
现在我要谱写自己的篇章
Fight my way to the ending that I want
拼搏直奔那理想的远方
I'll turn a tragedy
那一路的荆棘
Into an epic fantasy
会化为我不竭动力
Hey! Hey! Hey!
You can be a hero too
你就是那英雄 呦
Oh-oh-oh
Take my hand, I'm here for you
手拉手  因为朋友
Come away with me
快来随我前进
Be the legend you were meant to be
这份传奇由你来决定
You'll always be
你会明晰
Everfree
你的真谛
Oh, oo-wah, ah-oh, oo-wah, ah-oh, oo-wah
To be the legend you were meant to be
这份传奇就由你来决定
Oh, oo-wah, ah-oh, oo-wah, ah-oh, oo-wah
To be the legend you were meant to be
这份传奇就由你来决定
There was a time when fear would hold me down
心中恐惧曾让我迷惘
'cause I let it chain me to the ground
如枷锁在地捆住我脊梁
Look at me now, I'm soaring high
快看天高  我翩翩来
It's never boring in the sky
在这高处永远都精彩
When I know I've got friends on my side
当在我明白我朋友依然在
Whatever trials I'll take them all in stride
任何难关我们共同去担当
Together we will shine so bright
在一起我们最开怀
Radiant brilliance in the night
就算夜里光芒也自在
Hey! Hey! Hey!
You can be a hero too
你就是那英雄 呦
Oh-oh-oh
Take my hand, I'm here for you
手拉手  因为朋友
Come away with me
快来随我前进
Be the legend you were meant to be
这份传奇由你来决定
You'll always be
你会明晰
Everfree
你的真谛
Oh, oo-wah, ah-oh, oo-wah, ah-oh, oo-wah
To be the legend you were meant to be
这份传奇就由你来决定
Oh, oo-wah, ah-oh, oo-wah, ah-oh, oo-wah
To be the legend you were meant to be
这份传奇就由你来决定
Thank you all so much for coming.
十分感谢各位的光临
And for helping us raise enough money to... save Camp Everfree!
帮助我们筹到足够的钱去……拯救森灵营地
Thank you For everything.
谢谢你们所做的一切
Oh, if I'd just asked for help in the first place...
要是我一开始就向你们求助就好了
Heh, don't sweat it, it's kinda what we do.
哈, 小菜一碟, 这是我们应该做的
Not to brag or anything
不是我吹嘘
but it's pretty cool how I saved all those campers from those Rubus fruticosus.
但我把所有露营者从那些 Rubus fruticosus 里救出来真的非常酷
Blackberry brambles.
黑莓荆棘
I'm familiar with the genus
我对这种植物很熟悉
it's just a little weird you say you saved the campers.
只是你说是你救了那些露营者有点奇怪
I thought I saved them.
我以为是我救了他们
Yeah.
没错
But I saved you from falling on the docks
但我救了你, 没有让你跌到码头上
so that you can save the campers.
这样你才能救下那些露营者
So technically, it was on me.
所以严格来讲, 这都是我的功劳
I'm really glad I met you.
我很高兴能遇见你
Uh-oh.
啊哦
What?
怎么?
That sounds like a goodbye.
那听上去像是告别了
And here I was hoping we'd still be able to hang out.
我还想和你约个会来着
Maybe get dinner and catch a movie?
比如一起吃个饭看个电影什么的?
Yeah. I'd really like that.
嗯, 我很期待
Oh, good!
哦, 好极了
I was hoping that's what this meant.
我希望这话你是当真说的
Oh, uh, sorry.
噢, 呃, 抱歉
I need to borrow Timber.
我得拉走一下云杉
There are some donors I really want him to meet.
我真的需要让他去见见一些捐赠者
They were good friends with mom and dad.
他们都曾是爸爸妈妈的好友
Save me a dance, okay?
给我留一支舞, 好吗?
Uh-huh.
呃好
Adorable.
太可爱了
He does seem like a pretty cool guy.
他看上去确实是个很酷的家伙
You know what else is cool?
你们知道还有什么特别酷吗?
Our awesome new superpowers!
我们超棒的超能力!
I handed out, like, four hundred fliers
我发了大概, 四百张传单
set up the stage
搭建起舞台
and still had time to pick up pizza!
然后仍然能抽时间拿上披萨!
I love my superspeed!
我爱我的超级速度!
About that.
关于这个
I think the crystals are the source of the superpowers.
我想这些水晶就是超能力的来源
You're not gonna ask us to give them up, are you?
你没有想要我们放弃它们吧?
No.
不
In fact, I think maybe we were meant to have them all along?
事实上, 我想也许我们本来就该拥有它们?
Me too.
我也是
There is one thing I'm still wondering about, though.
不过有一件事我还是很想知道
What's that?
是什么?
Where did the magic that hit this cave come from?
飞进洞穴的魔法到底是从哪儿来的?
Somewhere's a book
有一本书
With chapters still blank inside
内容还都是空白
It's the book of our lives
这书是我们的生活
And the story is ours to write
故事要我们来编写
Some pages fade
有些书页褪色
While others are black and white
有些则变成黑白
And the story begins
故事再度开始
Again every time we try
只要我们去努力
And hope shines eternal
希望之光永照
And friends are all I need
朋友便是我所需
And hope shines eternal
希望之光永照
And the future is always bright
未来充满永恒的光彩
When you're here with me
只要你在我身边
I fought through the darkness
我努力穿过黑暗
And come out the other side
从另一边踏出来
For rain clouds will clear
乌云会为
The way for the sunny skies
晴朗的天空让开
I've been afraid
我曾畏惧
And stayed through the longest nights
熬过最长的夜晚
But morning still comes
但是早晨还会来
And with it, it brings a light
带来明媚的阳光
And hope shines eternal
希望之光永照
And friends are all I need
朋友便是我所需
And hope shines eternal
希望之光永照
And the future is always bright
未来充满永恒的光彩
The future is always bright
未来充满永恒光彩
Yeah, the future is always bright
未来充满永恒的光彩
When you're here with me
只要你在我身边
Third time is a charm.
第三次有好运
Or is it fifth?
或者是第五次?
I've lost track.
我快数不清了
All that matters is that the runway is finished.
总之这个 T 台终于修好了
I think you mean "the dock"?
我认为你是想说“码头”对吧?
Oh, tomahto, tomato.
哦，都一样了
Let's celebrate!
咱们欢庆竣工吧!